Junyoung Park

Website: pjywang.github.io Email: pjywang@kaist.ac.kr

Research Interests

I am generally interested in data analysis with unique geometric structures necessitating rigorous treatment. Much of my research focuses on **compositional data analysis**, including variable selection, dimension reduction, and predictive model development. I am also interested in the recent theory of kernel methods, notably conditional mean embeddings and sufficient dimension reduction.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Candidate in Mathematical Sciences

2018 - 2024

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST), Daejeon, Korea (Co)Advisors: Cheolwoo Park, Jeongyoun Ahn

B.S. in Mathematics

2013 - 2018

Korea University, Seoul, Korea

EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant in Statistical Learning

KAIST

Under the supervision of Prof. Cheolwoo Park and Jeongyoun Ahn

2021 - 2024

- Kernel methods, compositional data, dimensionality reduction, autoencoder clustering

Research Assistant in Algebraic Geometry

KAIST

Under the supervision of Prof. Sijong Kwak

2018-2021

- Projective geometry, syzygies, applied algebraic geometry
- Extensive training in geometry, algebra, and analysis at the graduate level and beyond

Max Planck Institute for Mathematics in the Sciences

Leipzig, Germany

Visiting research student

Summer 2019

- Attended Summer School on Randomness and Learning in Non-Linear Algebra

University Financial Engineering Association (U.FE.A)

Seoul, Korea

Team leader

2016-2017

- Led Master's-level financial engineering & mathematics studies
- Studied stochastic modeling and hedge (pricing) theory of various equity, interest rate derivatives

AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

• Presentation Award for Graduate Students, 2nd place, Korean Statistical Society (KSS)

2022

• The Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award, Calculus II, KAIST

Fall, 2020

- University Students Contest of Mathematics, Silver Awards, Korean Mathematical Society (KMS) 2016, 2017
- Presidential Science Undergraduate Fellowship, fully funded for 8 semesters

2013-2018

• The Korean Mathematical Olympiad (KMO) 2nd round of middle school division, Gold Awards 2009

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Park, J., Ahn, J., and Park, C. (2023), Kernel Sufficient Dimension Reduction and Variable Selection for Compositional Data via Amalgamation, In International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), pp. 27034-27047, PMLR (link).
- 2. Kang, I., Choi, H., Yoon, Y.-J., Park, J., Kwon, S.-S., and Park, C. (2023), Frechet Distance-Based Cluster Analysis for Multi-Dimensional Functional Data, Statistics and Computing, 33(4), 75.
- 3. Park, J., Yoon, C., Park, C., and Ahn, J. (2022), Kernel Methods for Radial Transformed Compositional Data with Many Zeros, In International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), pp. 17458-17472, PMLR (link).

In progress:

1. Interpretable Composition-To-Composition Dimension Reduction via Conditional Covariance Operator (with Jeongyoun Ahn and Cheolwoo Park), partially appeared in my Ph.D. dissertation.

Talks

• 2023 Winter Conference, the Korean Statistical Society Sungshin Women's University, Seoul, Korea

2023

- Title: Interpretable composition-to-composition dimension reduction via conditional covariance operator
- 40th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) (postered) Honolulu, HI, USA

2023

- Title: Kernel sufficient dimension reduction and variable selection for compositional data via Amalgamation
- 2023 Summer Conference, the Korean Statistical Society

2023

- Pukyong National University, Busan, Korea
- Title: Kernel sufficient dimension reduction and variable selection for compositional data via Amalgamation
- 2022 Fall KAIST Math Graduate student Seminar

2022

- KAIST, Daejeon, Korea
- Title: Kernel methods for radial transformed compositional data with many zeros
- 39th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) (spolight talk) Baltimore, MD, USA

2022

- Title: Kernel methods for radial transformed compositional data with many zeros
- Presented also at 2022 Summer Conference, the Korean Statistical Society, Seoul (awarded, 2nd place)

Teaching

- Teaching Assistant at KAIST (selected list)
 - Statistical Data Science Practice (DS516)

Spring 2023

- Probability and Statistics (MAS250)

Fall 2021

- Abstract Algebra I (MAS311)

Spring 2021

- Mathematical Statistics (MAS355)

Fall 2019

- Matrix Group Theory (MAS435) · Gave a guest lecture on connectedness of Lie groups in English Spring 2019

Fall 2018

Abstract Algebra II (MAS312)

 \cdot Gave several lectures throughout the semester

Computing Skills

- Python (for machine learning, statistics), R (for statistics), previous experiences with Matlab and C.
- Acceleration of optimization: experience in leveraging TensorFlow AutoGraph in my research.
- Parallel programming in R: foreach package, mclapply function in Linux environment.

LANGUAGES

- Korean (native)
- English

Hobbies

- Singing, better with playing guitar.
- Running, hiking, and climbing.

REFERENCES

Cheolwoo Park

Department of Mathematical Sciences and Graduate School of Data Science KAIST

parkcw2021@kaist.ac.kr

Sijong Kwak

Department of Mathematical Sciences KAIST sjkwak@kaist.ac.kr

Jeongyoun Ahn

Department of Industrial & Systems Engineering and Graduate School of Data Science KAIST jyahn@kaist.ac.kr